Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 3. Audio cassettes, 1966 - 1981; 3; Boxes: 1840 - 1844
  - Subseries 3.9: Miscellany, 3.9; Boxes: 1841 - 1844
    - Doctor Hung talk made by L. Thomas, undated (Folder 1843.25, Box 1843)
      Story told by Dr. Hung about the rising of Charlie Soong [father of Mrs. Chang Kai-shek; father of the most prominent family in 20th century of China]
    - Ray Virden, Lowell Thomas, Bob Armbruster, John Charles Thomas, Deems Taylor, Marc Connelly, Gene Lockhart, undated (Folder 1843.26, Box 1843)
    - Thurston Lecture, undated D (Folder 1843.27, Box 1843)
      Religion and history of Jerusalem
    - Talk by Doctor Ned A.G. Holsten, undated D (Folder 1843.28, Box 1843)
      1. Topic: “Footprints on the Sands of Time”
    - 12 - General Alexander Haig, undated (Folder 1843.29, Box 1843)
    - Pole to Pole, undated (Folder 1843.30, Box 1843)
      1. Includes radio transmission from Lowell Thomas to Lowell Thomas, Jr.
    - Summer Scout Camp Promotion Show, undated (Folder 1843.31, Box 1843)
      1. Narrated by Lowell Thomas, Sr. 2. Westchester - Putnam Council
    - KFH News, Undated (Folder 1843.32, Box 1843)
    - Dial M (Air), undated (Folder 1843.33, Box 1843)
    - “This is Cinerama”, undated (Folder 1843.34, Box 1843)
      1. Cypress Gardens 2. America the Beautiful
    - Lowell Thomas, Dayton number 2, undated (Folder 1843.35, Box 1843)
    - Lowell Thomas dictation tape, undated (Folder 1843.36, Box 1843)
    - Lowell Thomas presents the news of the day, undated (Folder 1844.01, Box 1844)
      1. A Lowell Thomas New Broadcast for NBC September 29, 1930 2. Part 3
    - Commemorating Charles Correll, undated D (Folder 1844.02, Box 1844)
      Andy from Amos ‘N’ Andy; death of Charles Correll; Clips from Amos ‘N’ Andy
    - Commemorating Charles Correll, undated D (Folder 1844.03, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.04, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.05, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.06, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.07, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.08, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.09, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Folder 1844.10, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.11, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.12, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.13, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.14, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.15, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.16, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.17, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.18, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.19, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.20, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.21, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, Undated (Folder 1844.22, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.23, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.24, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.25, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.26, Box 1844)
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 1844.27, Box 1844)
- 4. 16 millimeter magnetic tape, 1954 - 1957; 4; Box: 1844
  Series contains tapes on Tibet and miscellany
  - Subseries 4.1: Tibet, 1954; 4.1; Box: 1844
    - Tibet Original Recording, (release date) 1954 (Folder 81.01, Box 1844)
      “Out of This World,” Original, Voice Tape, magnetic tape
  - Subseries 4.2: Miscellany, 1957; 4.2; Box: 1844
    - Lowell Thomas broadcast - New Guinea report, 1957 May 7 (Folder 81.02, Box 1844)
      1. Reeves Soundcraft Corp. 16 mm Magnetic Recording Film Made in U.S.A. 10 East 52nd Street New York, New York 2. Recorder - Hoffman
    - Lowell Thomas broadcast - New Guinea report, 1957 May 7 (Folder 81.03, Box 1844)
      1. Roll 2 2. Reeves Soundcraft Corp. 16 mm Magnetic Recording Film Made in U.S.A. 10 East 52nd Street New York, New York 3. Recorder - Hoffman
    - Lowell Thomas broadcast - New Guinea report, 1957 May 7 (Folder 81.04, Box 1844)
      1. Roll 3 2. Reeves Soundcraft Corp. 16 mm Magnetic Recording Film Made in U.S.A. 10 East 52nd Street New York, New York
    - Lowell Thomas broadcast - New Guinea report, 1957 May 7 (Folder 81.05, Box 1844)
      1. Roll 4 - large roll 2. Reeves Soundcraft Corp. 16 mm Magnetic Recording Film Made in U.S.A. 10 East 52nd Street New York, New York 3. Recorder - Hoffman
    - Lowell Thomas broadcast - New Guinea report, 1957 May 7 (Folder 81.06, Box 1844)
      1. Roll 5 - small roll 2. Reeves Soundcraft Corp. 16 mm Magnetic Recording Film Made in U.S.A. 10 East 52nd Street New York, New York 3. Recorder - Hoffman
- 5. SoundScriber recordings, 5; Box: 1845
  - 1a and 1b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.01, Box 1845)
  - 2a and 2b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.02, Box 1845)
  - 3 and 3B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.03, Box 1845)
  - 4 and 4B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.04, Box 1845)
  - 5 and 5B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.05, Box 1845)
  - 41[?] and 42, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.06, Box 1845)
  - 43 and 44, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.07, Box 1845)
  - 45 and 46, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.08, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.09, Box 1845)
  - 2A and 2b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.10, Box 1845)
  - 3a and 3b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.11, Box 1845)
  - 4 and 4b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.12, Box 1845)
  - 5 and 5b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.13, Box 1845)
  - 6a and 6b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.14, Box 1845)
  - 7a and 7b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.15, Box 1845)
  - 8a and 8b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.16, Box 1845)
  - 1 and 1b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.17, Box 1845)
  - 1 and 2, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.18, Box 1845)
  - 2 and 2b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.19, Box 1845)
  - Blank, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.20, Box 1845)
  - Blank, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.21, Box 1845)
  - Blank, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.22, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.23, Box 1845)
  - 4a and 4, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.24, Box 1845)
  - 2B and 2, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.25, Box 1845)
  - 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.26, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.27, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1., circa late 1950s (Folder 80.28, Box 1845)
  - 2b and II, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.29, Box 1845)
  - 3 and 3a, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.30, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.31, Box 1845)
  - 2a and 2, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.32, Box 1845)
  - 2 and 3a[?], circa late 1950s (Folder 80.33, Box 1845)
  - 1a and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.34, Box 1845)
  - 2a and 2, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.35, Box 1845)
  - 4a and 4, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.36, Box 1845)
  - 3a and 3, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.37, Box 1845)
  - B and 2, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.38, Box 1845)
  - B and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.39, Box 1845)
  - 1A and 1[crossed out a], circa late 1950s (Folder 80.40, Box 1845)
  - B and 3, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.41, Box 1845)
  - 1 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.42, Box 1845)
  - 1 and B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.43, Box 1845)
  - 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.44, Box 1845)
  - b and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.45, Box 1845)
  - 1 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.46, Box 1845)
  - b and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.47, Box 1845)
  - 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.48, Box 1845)
  - 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.49, Box 1845)
  - B and 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.50, Box 1845)
  - July 1 and b a, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.51, Box 1845)
  - July 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.52, Box 1845)
  - July 3 and B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.53, Box 1845)
  - July 4 and B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.54, Box 1845)
  - 3 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.55, Box 1845)
  - 4 and B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.56, Box 1845)
  - 4 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.57, Box 1845)
  - 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.58, Box 1845)
  - 1A and 1b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.59, Box 1845)
  - 5 and B, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.60, Box 1845)
  - July 5 - and B., circa late 1950s (Folder 80.61, Box 1845)
  - B and 6, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.62, Box 1845)
  - B and 7, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.63, Box 1845)
  - B and 8, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.64, Box 1845)
  - Oct 2 and b, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.65, Box 1845)
  - b and Oct 1, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.66, Box 1845)
  - b and Nov 3, circa late 1950s (Folder 80.67, Box 1845)
- 6. Flexographs, 1940 - 1947; 6; Box: 1845
  - Bob Johanssen, undated (Folder 80.68, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.69, Box 1845)
    Has not been cut
  - Mr. Cole, 1947 (Folder 80.70, Box 1845)
    Reader’s Digest January 22nd, 1947
  - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1946 (Folder 80.71, Box 1845)
    S1: 6:45 9/9/46 S2: 6:45 9/10/46
  - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1946 (Folder 80.72, Box 1845)
    S1: 6:45 9/11/46 S2: 6:45 9/12/46
  - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1946 (Folder 80.73, Box 1845)
    S1: 6:45 9/13/46 [with photograph]
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.74, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.75, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.76, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.77, Box 1845)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Folder 80.78, Box 1845)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Folder 80.79, Box 1845)
    Blue case
  - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 80.80, Box 1845)
    WNBC “off the air” recording, Tuesday, January
  - Audiogram for Mr. Ditruars [sp?], undated (Folder 80.81, Box 1845)
    Second season’s report on the American Foundations Arabian Expedition conducted in association with the Carnegie Museum of Pittsburgh Wendell Phillips
  - Lowell Thomas, 1940 (Folder 80.82, Box 1845)
    WJZ; 6:45 12/3/40
  - Lord Morley, 1941 (Folder 80.83, Box 1845)
    Re: British Debt How the U.S. owes great Britain [sic] 5 billion dollars! July 9th, 1941
  - Thomas E. Dewey, 1944 (Folder 80.84, Box 1845)
    Election Eve Speech 11/6/44
  - Roosevelt, 1940 (Folder 80.85, Box 1845)
    Election Eve Speech November 9th, 1940
  - W. Willkie, 1940 (Folder 80.86, Box 1845)
    Election eve Speech 11/4/40
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.87, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.88, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.89, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.90, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.91, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.92, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.93, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.94, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.95, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.96, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.97, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.98, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.99, Box 1845)
  - “The Baron, He Say”, 1946 (Folder 80.100, Box 1845)
    Colonel Mashbir 9/6/46
- 7. Dictabelt recordings, 7; Box: 1845
  - 1, undated (Folder 80.102, Box 1845)
  - 2[?], undated (Folder 80.103, Box 1845)
  - 3, undated (Folder 80.104, Box 1845)
  - 4, undated (Folder 80.105, Box 1845)
  - X, undated (Folder 80.106, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.107, Box 1845)
  - Blank, undated (Folder 80.108, Box 1845)
- 8. Wire recordings, 8; Boxes: 1846 - 1847
  - Tolstoy talk, undated (Folder 46.01, Box 1846)
    1. 15 minute spool
  - Lowell Thomas - 3, undated (Folder 46.02, Box 1846)
    1. 30 minute spool
  - Kurdish voices at Kermanashah, undated (Folder 46.03, Box 1846)
  - Unidentified spool 1, undated (Folder 46.04, Box 1846)
  - Unidentified spool 2, undated (Folder 46.05, Box 1846)
    1. 60 minute spool
  - Unidentified spool 3, undated (Folder 46.06, Box 1846)
  - Unidentified spool 4, undated (Folder 46.07, Box 1846)
  - Unidentified spool 5, undated (Folder 46.08, Box 1846)
  - Unidentified spool 6, undated (Folder 47.01, Box 1847)
  - Unidentified spool 7, undated (Folder 47.02, Box 1847)
  - Unidentified spool 8, undated (Folder 47.03, Box 1847)
  - Unidentified spool 9, undated (Folder 47.04, Box 1847)
  - Unidentified spool 10, undated (Folder 47.05, Box 1847)
  - Flight to Berlin, 1945 April 24 (Folder 47.06, Box 1847)
    1. Eschwege, Germany 2. Armour Research Foundation - Magnetic Recording Wire
- 9. 8-Track cartridge, 1971; 9; Box: 1848 Folders: 1484.01
  - Pepnick Production, 1971 December 23 (Folder 1848.01, Box 1848)
    1. Box 333